Bad data visualizations can be summed up as visuals that don't convey your message well.
不良数据可视化指的是 不能将信息进行有效传达的图表
If a visualization is misleading or hides and distracts your message,
如果一个可视化具有误导性、隐藏或干扰了你想传达的信息
you need to consider changes to your visualization.
你就需要考虑对可视化进行优化
Let's look at some misleading examples.
我们来看一些具有误导性的例子
This is a popular image for showing bad visualizations.
这是数据可视化的一个著名反面例子
Here, you can see that this plot is misleading by making
我们可以看到这张图片具有误导性
a small difference seem much larger than it actually is by zooming in on the difference.
因为它将原本的较小差异放大 使得实际差距看上去非常大
This is a poor visualization due to the fact that it's misleading.
因为它的误导性 这是一个不良可视化
A second example was made popular by Cole,
第二个例子因 Cole 变得流行
who we mentioned in an earlier concept.
在前面的课程里 我们有提到过 Cole
Consider these two pie charts for understanding how
观察这两张饼图 来了解
a summer science camp for kids impacts their interests on learning about science.
参加科学夏令营是否影响孩子们对学习科学的兴趣
Can you tell if the camp was effective in raising the interest rates in science?
你是否能看出夏令营提升孩子对科学兴趣的效果？
This is an example of a visual that hides or distracts from the message.
这就是一个隐藏或干扰信息的可视化例子
Comparing the areas of the pie charts and
不论是通过比较饼图的区域大小
all the colors make it difficult to see the message.
还是查看不同颜色代表的含义 都不能很好地得出结论
Another plot from Cole's book is this pie chart.
Cole 还在书中给出了另一个例子 也就是这张饼形图
You might guess that this piece of the pie is the largest in terms of the suppliers.
你可能会觉得 这块区域所指的供应商份额是最大的
You would be wrong,
这你就错了
it's actually this piece.
实际上是这块
The 3D aspect of the chart is misleading.
图形的 3D 属性让人产生了误解
And, again, humans are not great at identifying differences based on these areas.
再强调一次 人类并不擅长识别基于面积的差异
Here is an example of a race track chart.
这里是一个赛道图的例子
Though one bar is clearly longer than the other,
尽管一个条形明显看起来比另一个长
they represent the same percentage.
它们却代表相同的百分比
This makes for some confusion.
这会让人困惑
Additionally, the bright red here suggests that this group is more important.
另外 这里的鲜红色表示该组更加重要
If this isn't the case,
如果这不是事实
then this coloring seems misleading.
这一颜色就看起来有误导性
With just two bars,
如果只有两个条形
we might not even need a chart but rather just a statement of the message.
我们甚至不需要绘图 而只需要用一个语句描述信息即可
Visualizations become more useful as
随着我们要传递的信息量变大
the amount of information we need to convey increases.
可视化会变得越来越重要
At the same time,
同时
adding extra elements to the visuals that do
那些额外的、不能传递数据信息的元素
not convey the message in your data should be avoided.
应避免添加到图形中
I urge you to strive for elegance and simplicity in your visuals.
可视化应该优雅和简洁
Here, you saw some examples of poor visuals.
这里 你了解了一些不良可视化的例子
You might have some ideas of how to improve these already.
你可能已经有一些改善图表的思路
We will look at some improved visuals in the upcoming concepts.
在接下来的课程中 我们将看到一些改善过的可视化